(
"ai_sub_version": "3.5.1",
"generated_at": "2026-08-02T00:25:19.028758",
"lyrics_prompt_version": 9,
"subtitles_prompt_version": 18,
"complete": true,
"max_retries_exceeded": false,
"any_pending": false,
"settings": (
"ai": (
"model": null,
"model_subtitles": "google-gla:gemini-3.5-flash-lite",
"model_lyrics": "google-gla:gemini-3.1-flash-lite",
"rpm": 4,
"tpm": 250000,
"google": (
"file_cache_ttl": 10,
"use_files_api": true,
"max_storage_gb": 18.0
),
"search": (
"qps": 0.3,
"max_length": 4096,
"web_search_tool": "langsearch",
"timeout": 60.0,
"retries": 3,
"min_wait_seconds": 1.0,
"max_wait_seconds": 10.0,
"multiplier": 2.0
),
"validation_buffer_ms": 2000,
"verification_gap_seconds": 60,
"gap_verification_retries": 1,
"gap_verification_ignore_start": true,
"gap_verification_ignore_end": true
),
"split": (
"max_seconds": 300,
"re_encode": (
"enabled": false,
"fps": 1.0,
"height": 360,
"bitrate_kb": 35,
"threshold_mb": 20,
"duration_tolerance_ms": 100,
"encoder": null
),
"start_offset_min": 0
"thread": (
"uploads": 4,
"re_encode": 2,
"lyrics": 4,
"subtitles": 4
),
"retry": (
"per_run": 5,
"max_runs": 3,
"multiplier": 2.0,
"min_wait_seconds": 30.0,
"max_wait_seconds": 300
),
"log": (
"level": "info",
"timestamps": true,
"scrub": false,
"progress_bars": true,
"progress_bar_width": 80,
"progress_bar_refresh_seconds": 1.0
)
あ！あ！
Ah! Ah!
うーん？！
Huh?!
うわぁーーっ！
Whoa—ah!
お客さま！席にお戻りください！
Customer! Please return to your seat!
みんな待ってるから行かないと！危ないですよ！
Everyone's waiting, I have to go! It's dangerous!
えっ？
Huh?
よいしょっ！
Heave-ho!
ちょっと！
Wait!
よいしょっ！
Heave-ho!
うわあああーーっ！
Waaaaah!
タノシイコトハジメヨウ
Let's get the fun started!
遊びたい ぜったい
I want to play, I definitely do!
JOY と JOY と JOY と POPなベイベー
JOY and JOY and JOY and a POP baby
JOY と JOY と JOY と HAPPYなピーポー
JOY and JOY and JOY and HAPPY people
キミノヒトミニスキスシテ
I want to kiss your eyes
笑いたい ぜったい
I want to smile, I definitely do!
JOY と JOY と JOY と YOUきなベイベー
JOY and JOY and JOY and YOU baby
JOY と JOY と JOY と HAPPYなSayイェー
JOY and JOY and JOY and a HAPPY Say yeah
君の心はそう もっと Do Do
Your heart, yeah, it wants to do do more
僕の心もそう いっそ Good Good
My heart does too, all the more good good
はじけてるんじゃない？ イッツ じょいふる
Aren't you bursting? It's joyful
JOY と JOY と JOY と POPなベイベー
JOY and JOY and JOY and a POP baby
JOY と JOY と JOY と HAPPYなピーポー
JOY and JOY and JOY and HAPPY people
この指に 止まるのは どんな運命なんだ
What kind of destiny will come to a halt at my fingers?
ぜんぶしたいな じょいふるだって終わっちゃう
I want to do it all, it's just so joyful
エビバディいつか終わっちゃう
Everybody will eventually come to an end
最終型は きっと修正なしで
The final form surely won't need any corrections
どづ We do We do We do Do
Do, we do we do we do do
ぴぷぺぽ ぱぴぷぺ 痛いっ! とうたいっ!
Pi pu pe po, pa pi pu pe, Ow! To do!
JOY と JOY と JOY と YOUきなベイベー
JOY and JOY and JOY and YOU baby
JOY と JOY と JOY と HAPPYなSayイェー
JOY and JOY and JOY and a HAPPY Say yeah
君の心はそう もっと Do Do
Your heart, yeah, it wants to do do more
僕の心もそう いっそ Good Good
My heart does too, all the more good good
はじけてるんじゃない？ イッツ じょいふる
Aren't you bursting? It's joyful
ぱぴぷぺぽばぶー JOY
Pa pi pu pe po babu~ JOY
どきどきしちゃうのはなんでだろう
Why is my heart beating so fast?
きずきづしちゃうのはなんでだろう
Why is my chest tightening so much?
この指にとまるのは どんな運命なんだ
What kind of destiny awaits me at the end of this finger?
ぜんぶスタイルの 傷だらけで終わっちゃう
It's all one big style, but it ends just like that
いつでもいつかこの時を
Every time, it always ends someday
最終形は きっと修整してく
Let's shape this final form with no regrets
We do, We do, We do, We do...
Pi pu pe po, pa pi pu pe...
JOY と JOY と JOY と YOUきなベイベー
JOY and JOY and JOY and YOU baby
JOY と JOY と JOY と HAPPYなSayイェー
JOY and JOY and JOY and a HAPPY Say yeah
ボクラノココロワソウマットウチュウ
Our hearts are always right in the middle
ブカツタツタハジケテルンジャナイ？
Isn't our youth bursting with energy?
いつJOYFUL BABI POPO BABU JOY
Always JOYFUL BABI POPO BABU JOY
おろせーや！
Lower me down!
おろしてあー！
Lower me down—!
ちゃんと おろせやーっ！
Lower me down properly—!
はい！ということで始まりました音乃瀬奏 生誕祭2025！
Alright! So kicking off, it's Kanade Otose's Birthday Festival 2025!
イエーイ！
Yay!
いやもう大変なんだって！
Man, it was so tough!
飛行機に乗ってここまで来るのにさ、うー、疲れた、もう疲れた！
Coming all the way here on a plane... Ugh, I'm so tired!
なんかこう、一応ハーネス取ってくるから、みんな待っててね！
Hold on, I'm gonna go get my harness, so everyone wait a sec!
えい！
Hup!
見ないで！えい！
Don't look! Hup!
はーい！
Hiiii!
なんと！なんと！えー、こちら
And guess what! Uh, here we have...
音乃瀬奏生誕祭2025、ハッシュタグは、「同じです！」
Otose Kanade Birthday Festival 2025, the hashtag is... "It's the same!"
あ、こっちに書いてある！こっちに書いてある通り、え、
Ah, it's written right here! As written right here, um...
音乃瀬奏生誕祭2025でいっぱいポストしてください！
please post a ton with Otose Kanade Birthday Festival 2025!
お願いします！
Please do!
そして今回は3Dになって初めての、あ、誕生日なので、いろんな新しいカラオケを皆さんに見てもらえたらなと思っています！
And since this is my first birthday in 3D, I hope you all get to enjoy all sorts of new karaoke!
そして最後には重大告知、あり！
And at the very end, there's a major announcement!
よかったら最後まで見てください！
If you'd like, please watch until the very end!
なんて、なんて、すごいコメントの、もうすごい速度...！
Man, the comments are going at such insane speed...!
ありがとう！
Thank you!
そしてゲストパートは一部収録です！生で歌ったり、え、ダンスしたりもするのでよかったら見守ってください！
And the guest part is partially recorded! We'll be singing live and dancing too, so please watch over us!
ありがとう！
Thank you!
からのじゃあ！
And now, tada!
お誕生日おめでとうー！
Happy birthday!
誰！？誰！？誰！？
Who?! Who?! Who?!
誰だっけ？誰だったかな忘れちゃった...
Who was it? Who was it again, I forgot...
え、来てくれたのー？
Eh, you came for me?
うれしーー！ありがとうよー！
So happyyy! Thank youuu!
首が、首が痛いんだよー！
My neck, my neck hurts!
あ、歌っていくから待っててね！
Ah, we're gonna sing, so wait for us!
来てくれたの、ありがとうー！
Thanks for coming!
来るか？来るか？何が来るんだ？
Is it coming? What's coming?
繋がっていたいって 信じられる言葉
"I wish to stay connected" I can believe those words
だってもう昨日の僕らにさよなら
While we say "farewell" to the people we were yesterday
青い春を過ごした 遠い稲妻
The blue spring had passed us by, a distant lightning strike
さっと泣いて 前だけを向けたら
If I could just cry and look straight ahead
きっとどんなに楽になれていたろな
Oh, how much easier it would have been
この心を揺らした 一縷の望みは
The faint hope that shook this heart of mine
ないものねだりは辞めた 未完成人間
I've stopped asking for what I can't have, an incomplete human
素晴らしい世界だけが 答えを握っている
Only this wonderful world holds the answers
諦めてしまうほど この先沢山の
So much that you'd want to give up, all the many regrets
後悔が君を待っているけれど
waiting for you in the future ahead
もうない 迷いはしないよ
But never more, no hesitation
この傷も愛しく 思えてしまうほど
It will add up to where you see your scars become endearing
重ねてしまうよ 不格好なままでいいから
It's all okay if it still feels out of shape
走れ その歩幅で 走れ 声響かせてくれ
So run with that stride, run and let your voice roar
期待と不安を同じくらい抱きしめて
Embrace excitement and anxiety just the same
君と今を紡ぐ未来照らし出して
Illuminate the future as we weave the present together
顔も名前も知らない僕たちが
We, who don't even know each other's faces or names
たった1つの音を鳴らし出す
Will ring out a single, unified note
いたずらみたいな奇跡のような刹那
A fleeting moment like a mischievous miracle
あっという間に流れる時間が
Time flowing away in the blink of an eye
ありのままで居続ける怖さが
The fear of continuing to stay just as we are
失った時間は取り戻せないけれど
Though we can never win back the time we've lost
繋がっていたいって 信じられる言葉
"I want to stay connected," words you can believe
だって もう昨日の僕らにおさらば
Saying goodbye to yesterday's us,
青い春を過ごした 遠い稲妻
We spent our blue spring like a distant lightning bolt.
さっと泣いて 前だけを向けたら
If we could just cry and look straight ahead,
きっとどんなに軽くなれていただろうな
how light we surely would have become.
この心を揺らした 一縷の望みは
The single ray of hope that shook this heart
ないものねだりは辞めた 未完成人間
I stopped asking for the impossible, an unfinished human.
いつしか 想いは 形になる
Someday, feelings will take shape.
この真っ白に染まる 朝 忘れられないまま
Remaining unforgotten in this pure white morning—
宝物だから 諦めてしまうほど
Because it's a treasure, to the point of giving up—
この先たくさんの 後悔が君を待ってるけども
Even though plenty of regrets await you ahead,
もう迷いはしないよ 駆け替えのないもの
I won't hesitate anymore; something irreplaceable
溢れてしまうよ 答えは君のその手の中に
overflows, and the answer is right there in your hands.
話さないで 物語は一歩前へ
Don't let go; the story takes a step forward.
諦めてしまうほど
To the point of giving up—
この先たくさんの 後悔が君を待ってるけども もう迷いはしないよ
Even though plenty of regrets await you ahead, I won't hesitate anymore.
この傷も愛おしく思えてしまうほど
To the point where even this scar feels dear,
壊されてしまうよ 不格好なままでいいから
it gets broken; it's fine just being clumsy.
走れ その歩幅で 走れ 声響かせてくれ
Run at that stride, run and let your voice resound.
期待と不安を同じくらい抱きしめて 君と今を紡ぐ未来照らして
Embrace expectation and anxiety equally, illuminating the future woven with you now.
顔も名前も知らない僕たちが たった1つの音をかき鳴らす
We, whose faces and names are unknown, strum just a single sound.
いたずらみたいな奇跡のような刹那 あっと言う間に流れる時間が
A fleeting moment like a mischievous miracle, time flowing in the blink of an eye.
ありのままで在り続ける恐ろしさ 失った時間は取り戻せないけれど
The terror of continuing to be as you are—though lost time cannot be regained,
過去を振り返ってばかりじゃ 泣いたっていいんだ 悔しさと痛みだけが君を肯定するから
looking back at the past all the time... it's okay to cry, because only regret and pain validate you.
ありがとう！ありがとう！改めておめでとう！ありがとう！
Thank you! Thank you! Congratulations once again! Thank you!
おめでとう！ありがとう！
Congratulations! Thank you!
そういえば 自己紹介してなくね？誰ですか？
Come to think of it, we haven't introduced ourselves, right? Who are you?
はい！
Yes!
え、かわいいポジティブジニアス！カナデの女 一条莉々華です！
Uh, cute positive genius! Kanade's woman, Ririka Ichijo!
ええ！？
Eh?!
一番最初は、ドキドキ始まり！
The very beginning, a pounding start!
え、これでののちゃんだよ。
Eh, this is Nono-chan's...
え、莉音ロスのジュフーテラディでございます！
Uh, I'm Jufuu Raden of the Rion loss!
音乃瀬奏の コーチ？コーチ？何教えたの？ みんなよ 教わった記憶ないの！そのカナデを… 逆なん？ どっちがコーチなのそれ？
Kanade Otonose's coach? Coach? What did you teach? Everyone... I have no memory of being taught! Kanade... Wait, is it the other way around? Which one is the coach?
ということで、莉音ロスの皆来てくれてありがとう！
With that said, thank you to all the Rion-loss fans for coming!
愛してる！めちゃくちゃ歌いたかったんだ！嬉しい！
I love you! I wanted to sing so much! I'm so happy!
次はゲストパートなんだけど、一緒にコール、お願いしてもいいかな？ もちろん！もちろん！じゃあ行くよ、せーの！
Next is the guest part, but would you mind joining in for a call? Of course! Of course! Then here we go, ready, go!
ねぇ 考えてなくてもいいよ 口先じゃ分かり合えないの
Hey, you don't have to think about it. We can't truly understand each other with just empty words.
この音に今は乗ろうよ 忘れないでいたいの
Let's ride this sound right now; I want to keep remembering it.
身体は無彩色レイドバック ただうねる雨音でグルーヴ
My body is monochrome, laid-back—just grooving to the swelling sound of rain.
ずっと二人で暮そうよ この夜の隅っこで
Let's live together forever in the corner of this night.
ねぇ 不甲斐ない僕らで
Hey, with our feckless selves—
誘ったのは君じゃないの
Wasn't it you who invited us?
ねぇ 出会いない僕らでいいよ 手探ったのは君じゃないの
Hey, it's fine if we have no encounters; wasn't it you who felt around in the dark?
理屈だけじゃつまらないわ まだ時間が欲しいの
Just logic is boring; I still want more time.
練り歩く景色を真空パック 踏み鳴らす足音でグルーヴ
Vacuum-packing the strolling scenery, grooving to the stomping footsteps.
まるで僕らはブレーメン たった二人だけの街
As if we are the Bremen town musicians, a town of just the two of us.
さあ息を吸って速く吐いて 精一杯歌っていこうぜ
Now, take a breath and exhale quickly, let's sing our hearts out!
笑うかい お前もどうだい 愛の歌を歌ってんのさ
Will you laugh? How about you too? We're singing a song of love.
さあ 盛大に歌ってようぜ 笑うかい お前もどうだい
Come on, let's sing grandly! Will you laugh? How about you too?
愛の歌を歌ってんのさ ああ
We're singing a song of love, ah—
さあ 盛大に合作してこうぜ 死ぬほどのことばこの世にないぜ
Come on, let's collaborate grandly! There's nothing in this world serious enough to die over.
明日は何しようか
What should we do tomorrow?
暇なら語り合おうぜ
If we're free, let's chat.
...
ねえ 考えなくてもいいよ
Hey, you don't even have to think about it.
踊り始めた君の細胞
Your cells have started to dance.
この世に今は呪いよ
Right now, curses in this world—
乗れなくてもいいよ
It's okay if you can't get into it.
想い出の景色でバックパック
A backpack filled with memories,
遥か風のざわめきでグループ
A group amidst the distant wind's murmur.
もっと二人で歌おうよ 暇なら愛をしようよ
Let's sing more together, let's share our love if we're free.
さあ 息を吸って
Come on, take a breath,
声に出して
And let it out in voice!
あー せいぜい歌ってよぜ
Ah, sing to your heart's content,
笑われてるのも仕方がないね
It can't be helped if people laugh at us.
何もかも間違ってのさ あはははは
Everything's gone wrong, ahahaha!
あー せいぜい楽して行こうぜ
Ah, let's take it as easy as we can,
馬鹿をよそおうのラグジュアリー
The luxury of playing the fool.
同じような貸し出し 三番は飛ばしていいよ
Similar rentals, you can skip number three.
さあ 息を吸って
Come on, take a breath,
早く吐いて
Breathe out quickly,
ねえ 心を貸して 今日ぐらいは
Hey, lend me your heart, at least for today.
あー せいぜい歌ってよぜ
Ah, sing to your heart's content,
違う顔 おまえらみんな 僕のこと笑ってんのかば
Different faces, are you all laughing at me?
あー せいぜい楽して行こうぜ
Ah, let's take it as easy as we can,
死ぬほど辛いね 逃げ出そうぜ
It's painfully hard, let's run away.
ずっと待てばきっと 一人も覚えてないよ
If we wait forever, surely no one will remember.
さあ ぜいぜい歌ってよぜ
Come on, sing gasping for breath,
体は動く おまえもどうだい
Your body moves, how about you too?
愛の歌って歌ってのさ あはははは
Singing a song of love, ahahaha!
あー せいぜい楽して行こうぜ
Ah, let's take it as easy as we can,
死ぬほどのことはこの世にないぜ
There's nothing in this world worth dying over.
明日は何しようか 暇ならわらいあおうぜ
What should we do tomorrow? If we're free, let's laugh together.
そのうち語り合おうぜ
Before long, let's talk it out.
改札の前 つなぐ手と手
In front of the ticket gate, hands holding hands,
いつものざわめき、新しい風
The usual commotion, a new breeze.
明るく見送るはずだったのに
I was supposed to see you off cheerfully,
うまく笑えずに君を見ていた
But I couldn't smile well as I looked at you.
君が大人になってくその季節が
As you grow into an adult, that season
悲しい歌で溢れないように
Won't overflow with sad songs,
最後に何か君に伝えたくて
Wanting to tell you something at the very end,
「さよなら」に代わる言葉を僕は探していた
I was searching for words to replace 'goodbye'.
君の手を...
Your hand...
改札の前 つないだ手と手
In front of the ticket gate, hands holding hands
いつものざわめき、新しい風
The usual commotion, a new breeze
明るく見送るはずだったのに
I was supposed to see you off cheerfully
うまく笑えず君を見ていた
But I couldn't smile well as I looked at you
君が大人になってくその季節が
As you grow into an adult, that season
悲しい歌で溢れないように
I wanted to convey something to you before it overflows with sad songs
最後に何か君に伝えたくて 「さよなら」に代わる言葉を僕は探してた
I was searching for words that would turn into "goodbye"
君の手を引くその役目が僕の使命なんて そう思ってた
Pulling your hand, thinking that was my mission... That's what I thought
だけど今わかったんだ ぼくらならもう
But now I understand, if it's us
重ねた日々がほら、導いてくれる
The days we spent together will guide us
君が大人になってくその時間が
As you grow into an adult, that time
降り積もる間に僕も変わっていく
As it accumulates, I also change
たとえばそこにこんな歌があれば
For example, if there's a song here
ふたりはいつもどんな時もつながっていける
The two of us can always stay connected
突然ふいに鳴り響くベルの音
Suddenly, the bell rings loudly
焦る僕 溶け出す 手離れてく君
I panic, our hands separate as you move away
夢中で呼び止め 抱き締めたんだ
I called out in a daze, embraced you
君がどこに行ったって僕の声で守るよ
No matter where you go, I'll protect you with my voice
君が僕の前に現れた日から
Since the day you appeared in front of me
何もかもが違ってみえたんだ
Everything seemed different
朝も光も涙も 歌う声も
The morning, the shining tears, the singing voice
君が輝きをくれたんだ
You gave me brightness
抑えきれない思いをこの声に乗せて
Carrying these uncontrollable feelings in my voice
遠く君の街へ届けよう
I'll send them far to your town
たとえばそれがこんな歌だったら
If it's a song like this
ぼくらは何処にいたとしてもつながっていける
We can stay connected no matter where we are
ずっと夢見てた僕になれたかな
It seems that I've gotten used to just living a dream
とうに帰れないとこまで来たみたい
It feels like I've reached the point of no return
自分の足で二段飛ばして
I jump up two stairs with my own feet
そうもっと先へ 駆け出していけるはずだからrun away
And run away because it looked like I'd keep going from there
深くなる傷を縫い付け
After stitching the deepening wound
繋ぐパス軸に巡り出す
The paths are connecting and springing away
慣れた痛み、焦る呼吸とビート
The usual pain, the beat and my breathing quickens
気付かないふりしてまた一人
Act as though I don't feel anything alone again
何が正当?ないない永劫
Who is right? There never is one
誰が間違った対価払うの
Who was wrong? Shouldn't they be compensated?
あんたが嫌いなあいつはきっとただ「それだけ」で不正解なんだ
That one you hate so much is surely just "like that"
0点だって提言したって 全然納得できない理由も
0 points? It's not accepted at all
最前線はいつだってここだった
The frontier was always here
最善策は最初からなかった
The best way wasn't there in the first place
緩やかに崩れ壊れてく
Slowly and gently, it crumbles and breaks
ゆるりゆるり首を締めするように昨日の僕が殺されていく
As if it's slowly, slowly choking, me of yesterday is being killed off
緩やかに離れ離れ飽う
Slowly and gently, our scattered ennui
ぐらりぐらり君にきこえるのは僕が知らない声になってく
When I hear you speak unethically, it turns into a voice I don't know
愛のネタバレ 「別れ」っぽいな
Love's spoiler: looks like "breaking up".
人生のネタバレ 「死ぬ」っぽいな
Life's spoiler: looks like "dying".
なにそれ意味深で かっこいいじゃん…
What's that, so profound and cool...
それっぽい単語集で 踊ってんだ 失敬
Dancing to a collection of buzzwords, excuse me.
とぅ とぅるる とぅ とぅ とぅるる 風
To- to-ruru- to- to- to-ruru style
ぽいじゃん ぽいじゃん
Sounding like it, sounding like it
とぅ とぅるる とぅ とぅ とぅるる 風
To- to-ruru- to- to- to-ruru style
とぅ とぅるる とぅ とぅ とぅるる
To- to-ruru- to- to- to-ruru
神っぽいな
So godlike
もういいぜ もういいぜ それ
That's enough, that's enough, right there
もういいぜ もういいぜ 逆に興奮してきたなあと
That's enough, I'm getting even more excited
おっけいいね おっけいいね 夢
Okay, nice, okay, nice, a dream
おっけいいね おっけいいね
Okay, nice, okay, nice
景気いいけど 品性はTHE END
Business is good, but class is at THE END
うええい うええい
Woah-ee, woah-ee
"Gott ist tot"
神っぽいな それ 卑俗
So godlike, how vulgar
神っぽいな それ "my god"
So godlike, oh "my god"
アイオウンチュー ウォウンチュー IQが下がっていく感じ
I want you, want you, feeling my IQ drop
邪心っぽいな それ 畢竟
So malicious, ultimately
邪心っぽいな それ "my god"
So malicious, oh "my god"
アイヘイチュー ヘイチュー 害虫はどっち
I hate you, hate you, which one is the pest?
その髪型 その目 その口元
That hairstyle, those eyes, that mouth
その香水 その服 そのメイク
That perfume, those clothes, that makeup
アレっぽいな それ 比況
Looks like that, how cowardly
アレっぽいな それ
Looks like that, right there
その名言 その意見 その批評
That quote, that opinion, that criticism
そのカリスマ そのギャグ そのセンス
That charisma, that gag, that sense
神っぽいな それ 卑俗
So godlike, how vulgar
っぽいな っぽいな っぽい
Like it, like it, like it
憧れちゃう!
I yearn for it!
とぅ とぅるる とぅ とぅ とぅるる 風
To- to-ruru- to- to- to-ruru style
ぽいじゃん ぽいじゃん
Sounding like it, sounding like it
とぅ とぅるる とぅ とぅ とぅるる 風
To- to-ruru- to- to- to-ruru style
とぅ とぅるる とぅ とぅ とぅるる
To- to-ruru- to- to- to-ruru
神っぽいな
So godlike
メタ思考する本質は悪意?
Is the essence of meta-thinking malice?
人を小馬鹿にしたような作為
A deliberate act of mocking people
無為に生き延びるのは難しい
Surviving idly is difficult
権力に呑まれて揺らぐ灯火
A light flickering, swallowed by power
神を否定し神に成り代わり
Denying god and taking god's place
玉座で豹変する小物達
Small fries changing colors on the throne
批判に見せかけ自戒の祈り
Self-reproach disguised as criticism
Do you know?
何言ってんの? それ ウザい
What are you saying? That's annoying
何言ってんの? それ 意味がよくわかんないし
What are you saying? I don't really get it
眠っちまうよ マジ
I'm gonna fall asleep, seriously
飽きっぴなんだよ オーケー
I'm getting tired of this, okay?
みんな飽きっぴなんだよ オーケー
Everyone's getting tired of this, okay?
踊れるやつ ちっちさいね 器
Anyone who can dance has a small vessel
天才ゆえ孤独ですね カッケー… カッケー…
Lonely because of genius, so cool...
"Gott ist tot"
神っぽいな それ 卑俗
So godlike, how vulgar
神っぽいな それ "my god"
So godlike, oh "my god"
超健康 健康 言い張って くたばっていく感じ
Super healthy, insisting on it as I drop dead
ヤケっぽいな それ 畢竟
Desperate, ultimately
ヤケっぽいな それ "my god"
Desperate, oh "my god"
もう哀愁 哀愁
Already sorrow, sorrow
そのタイトル その絵 その音楽 その歌
That title, illustration, music, song
アレっぽいな それ 比況
Looks like that, how cowardly
その名言 その意見 その批評
That quote, that opinion, that criticism
神っぽいな それ 卑俗
So godlike, how vulgar
っぽいな っぽいな っぽい
Like it, like it, like it
憧れちゃうわ!
I yearn for it!
とぅ とぅるる とぅ とぅ とぅるる 風
To- to-ruru- to- to- to-ruru style
ぽいじゃん ぽいじゃん
Sounding like it, sounding like it
とぅ とぅるる とぅ とぅ とぅるる 風
To- to-ruru- to- to- to-ruru style
とぅ とぅるる とぅ とぅ とぅるる
To- to-ruru- to- to- to-ruru
神っぽいな
So godlike
愛のネタバレ 「別れ」っぽいな
Love's spoiler: looks like "breaking up".
人生のネタバレ 「死ぬ」っぽいな
Life's spoiler: looks like "dying".
すべて理解して わざらっすた
Understanding everything, feigning it all
無邪気に踊っていたかった 人生
Wanting to dance innocently, my life
好き嫌い常識 i don't care 吹っ飛び
Likes, dislikes, common sense, I don't care
bang!!!
かかってこい majority あたしに負けはなし
Bring it on, majority, I have no defeats
ここまでって引かれたそのボーダー誰のルール？
That border drawn up to here, whose rule is it?
あの日乗り越えた weak heart
Overcoming that weak heart of that day
強くなったあたしが笑い飛ばしてあげる haha
The stronger me will laugh it all away, haha
言いたいことは言う
I'll say what I want to say
やりたくないことはしない
I won't do what I don't want to do
悪意気にしない皆違うの当然だし
Not caring about malice, everyone differs
あたしも変わらないニューノーマルの時代
And I won't change in this new normal era
(everybody say i want to be free)
yesもnoも言わない
Saying neither yes nor no
それじゃ何も変えられないな
That won't change anything at all
(everybody say i want to live more)
叶えたい自分肯定生きているんだあたし
Affirming the self I want to be, I am living
ねえ生きているんだあたし
Hey, I am alive
歌えや歌え今を (声上げて)
Sing, sing the present (raise your voice)
生まれたその時から選んできたんだ
I've chosen it ever since I was born
思い出せあたしはあたしだ
Remember, I am who I am
不可能なことなど何ひとつない嘘じゃない
There's not a single impossible thing, no lie
なりたい自分に
Into the self I want to be
好き嫌い常識 i don't care 吹っ飛び
Likes, dislikes, common sense, I don't care
bang!!!
好き嫌い常識 i don't care 吹っ飛び
Likes, dislikes, common sense, I don't care
bang!!!
フル10鳴らす
Turn it up to 10
このリリックかます
Drop this lyric
わかりす挑発
Provoke understandably
下向いて舌打ちからの「は？」
Looking down, clicking tongue, and saying "Huh?"
excuse me あしからず倍返し
Excuse me, double return, don't mind it
食らえパンチライン聞かせたげる
Eat this punchline, I'll let you hear it
やってから考えあたしがついてるから
Think after doing it, because I'm with you
(everybody say i want to be free)
過去の美徳習慣全部黙らせる shout
Silence past virtues and habits with a shout
(everybody say i want to live more)
目覚めさせ起きろ wake up, wake up
Awaken and rise, wake up, wake up
生きてるんだあたし
I am alive
ねえ生きているんだあたし
Hey, I am alive
生まれたその時から選んできたんだ
I've chosen it ever since I was born
思い出せあたしはあたしだ
Remember, I am who I am
不可能なことなど何ひとつない嘘じゃないの
There's not a single impossible thing, no lie
生まれたその時から選んできたんだ
I've chosen it ever since I was born
思い出せあなたはあなただ
Remember, you are who you are
不可能なことなど何一つない嘘じゃない
There's not a single impossible thing, no lie
なりたい自分に
Into the self I want to be
好き嫌い常識 i don't care 吹っ飛び
Likes, dislikes, common sense, I don't care
bang!!!
好き嫌い常識 i don't care 吹っ飛び
Likes, dislikes, common sense, I don't care
bang!!!
ローリングガールはいつまでも
Rolling Girl, forever dreaming
届かない夢見て
of an unreachable dream,
騒ぐ頭を掻き回して、掻き回して。
stirring up my noisy mind over and over.
「問題ない。」と呟いて、言葉は失われた?
Murmuring “No problem,” have my words been lost?
もう失敗、もう失敗。
Failed again, failed again.
もう一回、もう一回。
One more time, one more time.
私をどうか転がして
“Please make me roll,”
ローリングガールの成れの果て
The end of the rolling girl
届かない、向こうの色
is an unreachable color beyond,
重なる声と声を
overlapping voices
混ぜ合わせて、混ぜ合わせて。
mixing them together.
「問題ない。」と呟いた言葉は失われた。
The words murmured “No problem” were lost.
どうなったっていいんだってさ、
It doesn't matter what happens,
間違いだって起こしちゃおうと誘う、坂道。
a slope inviting us to make mistakes.
もう一回、もう一回。
One more time, one more time.
私をどうか転がして
“Please make me roll,”
少女は言う 少女は言う
the girl says, the girl says,
無口に意味を重ねながら!
piling meaning upon her silence!
好き嫌い 女子期 I don't care
Likes, dislikes, puberty, I don't care,
太っ腹ベイビー
generous baby!
好き嫌い 女子期 I don't care
Likes, dislikes, puberty, I don't care,
太っ腹ベイビー
generous baby!
ローリングガールはいつまでも
Rolling Girl, forever dreaming
届かない夢見て
of an unreachable dream,
騒ぐ頭を掻き回して、掻き回して。
stirring up my noisy mind over and over.
「問題ない。」と呟いて、言葉は失われた?
Murmuring “No problem,” have my words been lost?
もう失敗、もう失敗。
Failed again, failed again.
間違い探しに終われば、また、廻るの!
If we end up searching for mistakes, we'll go around again!
もう一度、もう一度。
One more time, one more time.
「私は今日も転がります。」と、少女は言う 少女は言う
“I'll keep rolling today,” the girl says, the girl says,
言葉に意味を奏でながら!
as her words play with meaning!
「もう良いかい?」
“Is it enough now?”
「まだですよ、まだまだ先は見えないので。」
“Not yet, I still can't see far ahead.”
息を止めるの、今。
“Hold your breath, now.”
「もう良いかい?」
“Is it enough now?”
「まだですよ、まだまだ先は見えないので。」
“Not yet, I still can't see far ahead.”
息を止めるの、今。
“Hold your breath, now.”
もう失敗、もう失敗。
Failed again, failed again.
間違い探しに終われば、また、廻るの!
If we end up searching for mistakes, we'll go around again!
もう一度、もう一度。
One more time, one more time.
「私は今日も転がります。」と、少女は言う 少女は言う
“I'll keep rolling today,” the girl says, the girl says,
言葉に意味を奏でながら!
as her words play with meaning!
「もう良いかい?」
“Is it enough now?”
「もう少し、もうすぐ何か見えるだろうと。」
“Just a little more, something will be visible soon.”
息を止めるの、今。
“Hold your breath, now.”
ローリングガールの成れの果て
The end of the rolling girl
届かない、向こうの色
is an unreachable color beyond,
重なる声と声を混ぜ合わせて、混ぜ合わせて。
overlapping voices mixing together over and over.
「問題ない。」と呟いた言葉は失われた。
The words murmured “No problem” were lost.
どうなったっていいんだってさ、
It doesn't matter what happens,
間違いだって起こしちゃおうと誘う、坂道。
a slope inviting us to make mistakes.
もう一度、もう一度。
One more time, one more time.
「私をどうか転がして」と
“Please make me roll,”
少女は言う 少女は言う
the girl says, the girl says,
無口に意味を重ねながら!
piling meaning upon her silence!
「もう良いかい?」
“Is it enough now?”
「もう少し、もうすぐ何か見えるだろうと。」
“Just a little more, something will be visible soon.”
息を止めるの、今。
“Hold your breath, now.”
もう一度、もう一度。
One more time, one more time.
「私は今日も転がります。」と、
“I'll keep rolling today,”
少女は言う 少女は言う
the girl says, the girl says,
言葉に笑みを奏でながら!
as her words play with a smile!
「もう良いかい? もう良いよ。そろそろ君も疲れたろ、ね。」
“Is it enough now? It's enough. You're probably tired too by now.”
息を止めるの、今。
“Hold your breath, now.”
空にある何かを見つめていたら
As I stared up at something in the sky,
それは星だって君が教えてくれた
you told me they were stars.
まるでそれは僕らみたいに
Just like us, they nestle close,
寄り添ってる
shining by our side.
空にある何かを見つめていたら
As I stared up at something in the sky
それは星だって君が教えてくれた
You told me they were stars
まるでそれは僕らみたいに寄り添ってる
Just like us, they nestle close
それを泣いたり笑ったり繋いでいく
At times crying, laughing, and connecting
何十回何百回ぶつかりあって
Clashing tens and hundreds of times
何十年何百年昔の光が
A light from tens and hundreds of years ago
星自身も忘れたころに
By the time the stars themselves have forgotten
僕らに届いてる
They reach us
僕ら見つけあって手を取り合って同じ空
We found each other, hand in hand, under the same sky
輝くのだって二人だって約束した遥か遠く
Promising to shine together, far, far away
終わらないベテルギウス
A never-ending Betelgeuse
誰かに繋ぐ魔法
Magic that connects someone to another
僕ら肩並べ手を取り合って進んでく
We stand shoulder to shoulder, hand in hand, moving forward
辛い時だって泣かないって誓っただろう
Vowing never to cry, even in times of pain
遥か遠く終わらないベテルギウス
Far and away, a never-ending Betelgeuse
君にも見えるだろう祈りが
You see the prayer too, don't you?
記憶を辿るたび蘇るよ
Every time I retrace my memories, they revive
君がいつでもそこに居てくれること
How you were always there for me
まるでそれは星の光と同じように
Just like the light of the stars
今日も泣いたり笑ったり繋いでいく
Today too, crying, laughing, and connecting
何十回何百回ぶつかりあって
Clashing tens and hundreds of times
何十年何百年昔の光が
A light from tens and hundreds of years ago
僕自身も忘れたころに
By the time I've forgotten it myself
僕らを照らしてる
It shines upon us
僕ら見つけあって手を取り合って同じ空
We found each other, hand in hand, under the same sky
輝くのだって二人だって約束した遥か遠く
Promising to shine together, far, far away
終わらないベテルギウス
A never-ending Betelgeuse
誰かに繋ぐ魔法
Magic that connects someone to another
どこまでいつまで生きられるか
How far, how long can we live?
君が不安になるたびに強がるんだ
Whenever you feel anxious, I act strong
大丈夫僕が横にいるよ
It's okay, I'm right beside you
見えない線をつなごう
Let's connect the invisible lines
僕ら見つけあって手を取り合って同じ空
We found each other, hand in hand, under the same sky
輝くのだって二人だって約束した遥か遠く
Promising to shine together, far, far away
終わらないベテルギウス
A never-ending Betelgeuse
誰かに繋ぐ魔法
Magic that connects someone to another
僕ら肩並べ手を取り合って進んでく
We stand shoulder to shoulder, hand in hand, moving forward
辛い時だって泣かないって誓っただろう
Vowing never to cry, even in times of pain
遥か遠く終わらないベテルギウス
Far and away, a never-ending Betelgeuse
君にも見えるだろう祈りが
You see the prayer too, don't you?
空にある何かを見つめていたら
As I stared up at something in the sky
それは星だって君が教えてくれた
You told me they were stars
透明よりも綺麗なあの輝きを確認にいこう
Let's go verify that brilliance, more beautiful than transparency
そうやって始まったんだよたまに忘れるほど強い理由
That's how it all began, a reason so strong we sometimes forget
冷たい雨に濡れる時は足音比べ騒ぎながらいこう
When caught in the cold rain, let's compare footsteps and make a noise
太陽の代わりに謳を君と僕と世界の声で
Singing a song in place of the sun, with the voices of you, me, and the world
いつか君を見つけた時に君に僕も見つけてもらったんだな
When I found you someday, you must have found me too
今目が合えば笑うだけさ言葉の外側で
Now, if our eyes meet, we just smile beyond words
透明よりも綺麗な あの輝きを確かめにいこう
Let's go confirm that radiance, clearer than transparency,
そうやって始まったんだよ
That's how it all began.
たまに忘れるほど強い理由
A reason so strong we sometimes forget it,
冷たい雨に濡れる時は 隣で
When we get soaked in the cold rain... right by your side.
君の側で 虫がここないよと叫ぶ
Right by your side, screaming that bugs won't come near.
泣いたり笑ったりするとき
When we cry or laugh,
君の命が揺れるとき
When your life trembles,
誰より (近くで) 特等席で
More than anyone, right up close, from the best seat,
僕も同じように息をしていたい
I want to be breathing just the same way.
Oh yeah, yeah, ah
君の一歩は僕より遠い 間違いなく君の凄いところ
Your every step is farther than mine, without a doubt, that's your amazing side.
足跡は僕の方が多い 間違いなく僕の凄いところ
My footprints are more numerous than yours, without a doubt, that's my amazing side.
真っ暗闇が怖いときは 怖さを比べ ふざけながらいこう
When pitch darkness is scary, let's compare our fears and joke around as we go.
太陽がなくなって歩ける 君とって照らす世界が見える
Even without the sun to walk by, I can see the world you illuminate.
言えないこと 聞けないままで 消えない傷の意味知らないままで
Unable to say it, unable to ask, not knowing the meaning of scars that won't fade,
でも 目が合えば笑えるのさ 涙を挟んでも
But if our eyes meet, we can smile, even holding back tears.
転んだら手を貸してもらうよりも
Rather than having you lend a hand if I fall,
優しい言葉選んでもらうよりも 隣で
Rather than having you choose gentle words... right by your side.
信じてほしいんだ どこまでも一緒に行けると
I want you to believe we can go anywhere together,
ついにたどり着くその時 夢の正体に触れるとき
And when we finally reach that moment, when we touch the true form of our dreams,
必ず (近くで) 一番側で 君の目に映る景色にいたい
Always, right up close, right by your side, I want to be in the scenery reflecting in your eyes.
あの輝きを確かめにいこう
Let's go confirm that radiance.
Oh yeah, yeah, ah
どんな最後が待っていようと もう離せない手を繋いだよ
No matter what ending awaits us, I held the hand I'll never let go.
隣で 隣で 君の側で 虫がここないよと叫ぶ
Right by your side, right by your side, screaming that bugs won't come near.
そして理由が光るとき 僕らを理由が抱きしめるとき
And when the reason shines, when the reason embraces us,
誰より近くで 特等席で 僕の見た君を君に伝えたい
More than anyone, up close, from the best seat, I want to tell you about the you I saw.
君がいることを君に伝えたい
I want to tell you that you are here.
そうやって始まったんだよ
That's how it all began.
Oh yeah, yeah, ah
わー、ママたちがいっぱいだー！
Wow, there are so many mamamas!
かなちゃん、お誕生日おめでとうー！
Kanatan, Happy Birthday!
お誕生日おめでとう！
Happy Birthday!
ありがとう！めでたい、めでたい！
Thank you! So celebratory!
生々しいな！
That sounds so raw!
お上に言われたくないよ！
You're one to talk!
だって誕生日だから！
Well, because it's my birthday!
お母さんたち生んでくれてありがとうございます！
Thank you to our moms for giving birth to us!
生んではない！
You weren't!
こちらこそ！
Likewise!
そして今日は何話すんですか？ここから何？
And what are we talking about today? From here, what?
そうですね、えーっと、これまでのコラボでも感想...
Let's see, um, impressions of our collabs so far...
もうめっちゃんこ色々したのよ！
We've done so many various things!
大丈夫かな？
Will we be okay?
じゃあ一番印象深かったの何？かなちゃんが。
Then what was the most memorable one, Kanachan?
そうだよね、でも、ゆうてこママズでやったコラボって...
That's right, but you know, collabs we did as YuuteKo Mamas...
実は1個しかない。
Actually, there's only one.
ああー懐かしい！あんた!
Ahh, nostalgic! It was you!
あれ、でもそういえばなんか赤い髪の毛の人...
Huh, but come to think of it, someone with red hair...
おれ？あんた！やっぱあれじゃない？生んだとか言う
Me? You! Wasn't it that thing where someone said "I gave birth" or something?
あ、でもなんかあれじゃん、スケジュール的に...
Ah, but you know, schedule-wise...
あ、そうだった！そうだった！
Ah, that's right! That's right!
次はね、みんなできるといいね！
Next up, I hope everyone can do it!
コラボとかもさ、あるよね？
There'll be collabs and stuff too, right?
したい、したい！
I want to, I want to!
よかった、よかった！
That's great, that's great!
あのゲームコラボ以来ですからね。
Because it's been since that game collab.
そうだね。
That's right.
はい、えっと…
Yes, um...
次ある？
Is there a next one?
一生、一生、一生…
Forever, forever, forever...
そうだね、えっと、そうですね。
That's right, um, that's right.
一生のへんかから言っていきますと、まずスバルまんまは
Starting from our life changes, first, Subaru-manma is...
これかな？のかなちゃんが言うんじゃない？
Is this it? Kanana-chan is going to say it, right?
必ずさ、なんかこれ一生…
Always, like, this forever...
そっちか！
That way?!
え？
Huh?
え、じゃあ聴きたい！聴きたい！
Eh, then I wanna hear it! I wanna hear it!
どっちから行く？どっちから行く？
Which one goes first? Which one goes first?
え、どっちにしようかな。ちゃんめい積んで、こっち！あ、スバルちゃんから？どっち？どっち？
Um, which should I choose? Stack Chanmei, this way! Ah, from Subaru-chan? Which? Which?
こっちはスバルなんだ。
This side is Subaru.
カナデは最初は、なんかARKで騒いでるの見て、なんかこいつと思って…
At first, when I saw Kanade making a fuss in ARK, I thought, 'Who is this?'...
なんだこいつ！
'What's with this guy?!'
そのARKで、あの声が貫通してる頃から、ホロライブメンバーの中では、カナデは大丈夫なんだなっていう…
Ever since that voice was piercing through in ARK, among Hololive members, I felt Kanade would be fine...
大丈夫なんだ！こういう子は大丈夫なんだっていう…
'She'll be fine! A kid like this will be fine...'...
なんか元気さが、あったんですよ。でもね、
There was this energetic vibe. But you know,
GTAで最後ね、かなちゃんがね、逮捕した時、もうその顔忘れられない。
when Kana-chan made that arrest at the end in GTA, I can't forget that face.
近いね！
That's close!
なんか逮捕したりとかね。
Like making arrests and stuff.
なんかそのあとかなちゃん、実はね、私もっと頑張りたいんです！ね？なんか電話してきたりとかね。
And then after that, Kana-chan, actually, 'I want to work harder!' Right? Like calling me up.
え、それ言っていいの！？
Eh, is it okay to say that?!
だからね、話したの。頑張り屋なんだんだなって思いました。
That's why I talked about it. I thought she's a hard worker.
おめでとう！誕生日おめでとう！
Congratulations! Happy birthday!
じゃ、そして次は？
Well, and next?
え、次は？え、次は？
Eh, next? Eh, next?
や、かなでちゃんはね、最初デビューした時さ、すごい歌もうまくてね、団長とはなんか、別世界の人間なんだなと思って全然絡めなかったけど…
Well, Kanade-chan, when she first debuted, her singing was so good, and I thought she was someone from a different world than Danchou, so we couldn't interact much...
いやでもね、マイクラでね、褒めてるあのダイヤをね、団長から、あの…
Well, but in Minecraft, those diamonds you praised, from Danchou, um...
うん、嘘ついてね、トータリとか。いやそっか！
Yeah, lying about it, totally. No, I see!
あ、この子はそういう子なんだ。
Ah, this kid is that kind of person.
あ、結構、ダイヤ、ダイヤ嘘ついて盗むようなやつ…
Ah, quite the type to lie and steal diamonds...
違うの、いやこんなね、団長にもこうやって、そう、あの、物も言えずね、絡んできてくれたりも本当かわいいの。
No, it's not like that! Even with Danchou like this, coming up and interacting with me without hesitation, she's really cute.
え、でも、ノエルママんまだったら何でも許してくれるの？
Eh, but if it's Noel-mama, you'll forgive her for anything?
いやもう許すじゃ…いやダメじゃん！ダイヤ盗むのは！
I mean, forgiving... No, that's not okay! Stealing diamonds!
いい子、いい子だから、今ではね。
She's a good girl now, though.
え、どんどん後ろ行くのやめて！
Eh, stop moving further and further back!
今ではね、本当にいい子です、本当。そうやね、本当に頑張ってくれた…
Now she's a really good girl, truly. That's right, she really worked hard...
え、頑張ってくれたんだ、なんかほめてくれた。
Eh, she worked hard, she praised me.
はい、でも本当ににおめでとうね、お誕生日。おめでとう！
Yes, but truly congratulations on your birthday. Happy birthday!
来てくれてありがとう！
Thank you for coming!
一緒に歌えいて本当に嬉しかったし、楽しかったぞ～！すわれ、立つのも嬉しかったぞ～！
It made me so happy and fun to sing together! Sitting down, standing up made me happy too!
え、どういうこと？どっち！どっちが！
Eh, what do you mean? Which one?! Which one!
じゃ、はい！かなでちゃん、次次次！次があるよ。
Well, yes! Kanade-chan, next, next, next! There's a next one.
めっちゃ台本読めば？え、お前だよ！お前じゃん！
Why don't you read the script properly? Hey, it's you! It's you!
お前だからどこ書いても、ちゃんとちゃんと読みます。
Because it's you, wherever it's written, I'll read it properly.
スバルママ！ノエルママ！
Subaru-mama! Noel-mama!
なんと、かなでがなんと、生パフォーマンスで一人で頑張るのを、すごーく！
Amazingly, Kanade will do her best alone in a live performance—
作りしてくれてもいいですか？いーよー！やったー！
Would it be okay for you to make it for me? Sure! Yay!
次の曲は、ビューティフル！
The next song is Beautiful!
遠くに伸びる影 夜の波が消した
The shadow stretching into the distance was erased by night's waves,
涙を流したなんて 気づかれないまま
without anyone ever noticing that I shed tears.
心を捨てるなら 傷付く方がマシさ
If I had to throw away my heart, getting hurt would be better.
冷たい風を切って 逃げるように走る
Cutting through the cold wind, I run as if to escape.
いつか この雨は 宝石になるのでしょう
Someday, this rain will surely turn into jewels.
美しい心に 生まれ変わる そう信じて
Reborn with a beautiful heart, believing in that,
世界で一つの 輝く光になれ
become the one and only shining light in the world.
私でいい 私を信じてゆくのさ
I am fine just as I am, believing in myself as I go.
どんなに遠くても 何があっても この道をゆけ
No matter how far, no matter what, walk down this path.
私でいい 私の歩幅で
It's fine to be me, at my own pace,
生きていくのさ
I will keep living on.
誰かと比べるのは 避けられない感情
Comparing yourself to others is an unavoidable emotion.
誰かを許すのは 難しい感情
Forgiving someone is a difficult emotion.
ないものを探せば 数えきれないけれど
If I search for what I lack, the count is endless,
ゆっくり愛してみよう
but let's try loving them slowly.
私だよ この命を 世界で一つの
It's me, this life, the one and only in the world.
輝く光に紛れ 明かりのない明日を迎えたとしても
Even if I get lost in the brilliant light and face a tomorrow without a lamp,
悲しみの先に 孤独が押し寄せても 息をしてる 今日も息をして 生きている
even if loneliness surges beyond the sadness, I am breathing, breathing today too, and living.
息をしてる 今日も息をして 生きている
I am breathing, breathing today too, and living.
世界で一つの 輝く光に紛れ
Lost in the one and only brilliant light in the world,
泣いてもいい 私を歩いてゆくのさ
it's okay to cry, I will walk as myself.
涙はほら 流れる星のように
Tears are, look, like falling stars,
私になれ 私を叶えて 生きていくのさ
become myself, make my dreams come true, and live on.
いつの日も
Always, through every day...
Always...
はい、という片手 いかがでしたでしょうか。ちょっとお水だけ飲んできます！
Yes, how was that one-handed song? I'm just gonna go grab some water!
水補給！
Water break!
はい、それでは、えー、この素晴らしい曲の余韻が消える前に、最後の曲、聴いてください！
Yes, well then, before the afterglow of this wonderful song fades away, please listen to the final song!
はいっ！
Ready!
目を開けて 口ずさむ 輝ける
Opening my eyes, humming, shining bright—
“きっと 無敵になる”
"I will surely become invincible."
feel my heart
See me become the GREATEST
No one can beat me
Cuz I'm a GREATEST
固く結び直した靴紐が 羽に見えて
The shoelaces I tied tightly again look like wings,
どこまでも跳べる 予感がする
giving me the feeling I can fly anywhere.
追いかけるなんて趣味じゃない 追い越そう 明日だって
Chasing others isn't my hobby; let's overtake even tomorrow,
夢のまま終わるほど眠くないわ
I'm not sleepy enough to let it end just as a dream.
そう 何もかも大丈夫
Yeah, everything will be fine.
奇跡よりも大胆に勝つの
Winning more boldly than miracles.
見たことない景色だって光に
Even scenery I've never seen before
満ちていく
is filling with light.
Wanna be the GREATEST 地図ならばこの胸に
Wanna be the GREATEST, if there's a map in my chest,
走る熱がある
there's a surging passion.
誰も止められない my way
Nobody can stop my way.
Wanna be the GREATEST
弱音も重ねればシンフォニー強く歌って
if we layer our weaknesses into a symphony, sing strongly,
強くなれる 歌って
Sing a song that makes you stronger.
“きっと 無敵になる”
“I'll surely become invincible.”
Feel my light
部屋で一人描いたステージも
Even the stage I drew alone in my room
覚えていて居場所になる
is remembered and becomes my place.
声が聞こえてくる
Voices are coming to me.
深呼吸をして飛び乗るぐらいが正攻法だって
Taking a deep breath and jumping in is the orthodox way,
胸を張って踊るのも悪くないわ
so dancing with pride isn't bad at all.
恐れないで大丈夫
Don't be afraid, it's okay.
唱えるたび「絶対」になるの
Every time I chant it, it becomes 'absolute'.
一度きりの人生だってこの手で舵を取れ
Even if life is only once, take the helm with this hand.
Wanna be the GREATEST
私が私として
as myself,
輝ける道を行く
I'll walk the shining path.
声もきらめいて my day
My voice also sparkles, my day.
Wanna be the GREATEST 目覚めを奏でてオーバーチュア
Wanna be the GREATEST, play the awakening overture.
望むほどに叶って
Granting as much as I wish,
もっと 素敵になる Feel my light
I'll become even more wonderful. Feel my light
Feel my heart
See me become the GREATEST
No one can beat me
Cuz I'm a GREATEST
Wanna be the GREATEST
諦めた「好き」の数
The number of things I gave up loving
上を向く理由がある
is why I have a reason to look up.
涙導いて my beat
Tears guide my beat.
Wanna be the GREATEST
傷跡も連れてアレグロ
Allegro, bringing my scars along too.
強く慣れる 歌って
Sing a song that makes you stronger
もっと 光差す方へ
Toward the place where light shines brighter
“きっと 無敵になる”
“I'll surely become invincible.”
ということで、
And with that,
今聞いていただいたのが、え、じゃなくて
what you just listened to is, uh, no,
え、ガチャロゴが曲?
Wait, Gacha Logo is the song?
そうですね、どういう曲か、え、すごい、
Right, what kind of song is it, uh, amazingly,
いうと、が、こう、簡単に言うと、え、韓国から夢をかけにきた「韓国ノリのこ」ギラギラソング、キラキラソング、みたいな感じとなっていまして、
to put it simply, uh, coming from Korea to fulfill her dream, a 'Korean-vibe' flashy song, sparkling song, something like that,
韓国がこういうのを信じてやっていきたいんだみたいなのを伝えて、え、描いていただきました。すごい、なんて素敵な歌詞を、本当に素敵な、え、楽曲と歌詞、ありがとうございます！めっちゃ気に入ってます！
she wanted to believe in and do this kind of thing from Korea, so she expressed that, and drew it for us. It's so amazing, what wonderful lyrics, truly wonderful, uh, music and lyrics, thank you so much! I love it so much!
そして、4月21日 0時から、え、この後おそらく3時、あ、違う、3時間後に、え、楽曲リリースもされます！イェーイ！ぱちぱち！ありがとう！
And, April 21st at 0:00, uh, probably 3 hours later from now, ah no, 3 hours later, uh, the music release will also happen! Yay! Clap clap! Thank you!
MVはね、ちょっと後日公開なんですけれども、ぜひ公開されたらいっぱい見てください！はい、新曲の披露もできたところで、
The MV will be released a bit later, but please watch it a lot when it comes out! Yes, now that we've premiered the new song,
告知タイムです！まず1つ目は、皆さんお待ちかね、グッズの紹介です！
it's announcement time! First is the merchandise introduction everyone's been waiting for!
それではグッズ1つずつ見ていきましょう！
So let's go through the goods one by one!
1つ目！
Number one...
ワイドラバーマット！
Wide rubber mat!
キービジュアルのオリジナルパジャマを着たきあデザインのラバーマットです！
This features an original pajama key visual design by gomzi!
2つ目は、こちら！
And number two is this!
が落書きしちゃったTシャツです！
A T-shirt featuring Kanade's own doodle!
あの実際にがね、描き下ろしデザインのTシャツです！描きましたー！
This actually has a doodle drawn by Kanade herself!
よかったらと一緒にTシャツ1枚持ってるために買ってくれませんか？いっぱい買ってくださーい！
I hope you'll buy one and wear it together with Kanade!
そして3つ目！
And number three...
タンブラーです！
The tumbler!
こちらのリボンをモチーフにした日常使いができる落ち着いたデザイン！
Featuring a stylish design with a ribbon motif that's easy to use every day.
会社などで使って、ぜひともを宣伝してください！
Use it at work and show off Kanade everywhere!
そして次は、こちら！
And next is this!
のぷにぷにクッション！
Kanade's squishy cushion!
ま、いっか。寝ている表情のフェイスクッションです。
It's a face cushion with a sleeping expression!
特別にのほっぺをぷにぷにしてよって台本に書かれていますが、きょ、恐れした覚えはありません！ぷにぷじゃないからな！
And while the script says she's wearing squishy clothes, she's definitely not squishy!
そして、フルセット購入特典は、こちら！
And now for the full set purchase bonus!
直筆サイン&箔押し複製メッセージ入りポストカード！
A postcard with a handwritten signature and duplicated stamped message!
今回数量限定ではないので、フルセット買ってくれた方全員に直筆サインが届きます！
Since there's no quantity limit this time, everyone who buys the full set is guaranteed to get the handwritten signature!
みんな安心してね！戦争じゃないからゆっくり買っていいんだぞ！がにだんだんになりながら書くからね！ふぁあ、頑張って書くぞー！
Rest assured, this isn't a marathon, so feel free to take your time!
さらにフルセット特典として
And as an extra full set bonus...
昨年の9月から発売されたホロライブオフィシャルカードゲームで使用できるカードが1枚付きます！
You'll get one card you can use in the Hololive Official Card Game released last September!
カードはホロライブプロダクションオフィシャルショップで購入された方のみ対象となります！か、可愛い！
This is exclusive to purchases on the Hololive Production Official Shop! Isn't it cute?
特典につくのはアピールできるPカード、お支払いの面カードです。
It's a PR card you can use to appeal!
カードの詳細や遊び方についてはホームページにてご確認ください。カードは日本語版のみとなりますのでご了承くださーい。
Please check the homepage for details on the card and how to play. The card is only available in Japanese, so please understand.
以上グッズ紹介でした！
That's all for the merchandise introduction!
そして、告知2つ目は、こちら！
And the second announcement is this!
なんと！LINEスタンプ制作決定です！すごーい！
LINE stamps are officially in production!
可愛いでしょう！すまそーって！すまそーってやってる！ぱちぱちありがとう！
Aren't they cute? They're so "Sumaso"! Doing the "Sumaso" pose—thank you so much!
発売日はまだ未定ですが、こんな感じの可愛いイラストのスタンプです！
The release date is still TBD, but we'll have cute stamps like these coming your order!
セリフとかもね、が考えて作ってもらっているので、こうご期待！詳細は後日また告知をします！お楽しみに！
We're thinking of including catchphrases too, so look forward to it! Details will be announced later!
以上告知でした！
That's all for the announcements!
ということで、とせかなで生誕祭2025！あ、違う、こちらだ！毎回間違える、2025！はい。
And that wraps up the Otonose Kanade Solo Live 2025... Wait, I always get the year wrong—2025!
いかがでしたでしょうか！
How was it?
初めてのね、アオリ曲の挑戦だったり、すごくかっこいいってコメントしてくれたの見たよ！
It was my first time challenging original songs, and I saw all your comments saying "so cool!"
嬉しかったし、すごい頑張って準備したので、あのいっぱい見ていただけて嬉しい限りです！
I'm so happy, and since I worked really hard to prepare, I'd be so happy if you watched it a lot!
もう本当に嬉しいよ！オリジナル曲も公開できて、
I'm truly happy! The original song is finally going to be released!
あの、リリースされたらいっぱい聞いてね！
And once it's released, stream it a lot!
すごいまたコメント欄がぷにぷにのくだりになってる。
Wait, the comment section is just a stream of "Puni Puni"s!
おっセンサー予測して打って、拾えんだろ。
Come on, predict the sender and find it!
えー、ということで、えー、この後のスケジュールをちょっとざっくり皆めにお教えしますと、21時10分からグッズ販売開始を行います！
So, let me briefly go over the schedule for afterwards: goods sales will start at 9:10 PM!
そして、21時20分から、あ、こちら。20分からメンバーシップ限定のアンコールライブ、アンコールライブもありますので、そちらもよろしくお願いしまーす！
And at 9:20 PM, there will be an Encore Live exclusively for members, so we would appreciate your support there too!
今が命の買い時だよ、みんな！今、今、今、今入りな。
Everyone, I'm the real-life God. Right now, right now, right now—yes, right now!
たぶんもう終わるから忘れちゃいけないよね。
And honestly, I almost forgot about my stamina!
はい、ということでじゃあ、おつー！
Well then, goodbye!
来てくれてありがとー！
Thank you for coming!
イエーイ！
Yay!
あ、待って待って待って待って！待って待って待って待って！
Wait, wait, wait, wait, wait, wait!
待って待って！
Wait, wait, wait!
一番大事なの忘れてた！
I almost forgot the most important thing!
一番大事なお知らせ！
The single most important announcement!
はい、告知！それでは、皆さん聞いてください。からねからのもうオリジナル曲、何に大事なお知らせ。
Yes, an announcement! Please listen, everyone—this is Kanade's most important announcement regarding her original song!
あしたは月曜日！
Tomorrow is Monday!
月曜日！月曜日！みんな夢から覚める時間だよー。もう夢から覚める時間だよー。
Monday, Monday. Everyone, it's time to wake up from your dreams.
からの生誕ライブはアンコールライブが終わったらもう終わりなんだよー。
Kanade's solo live... well, once the encore live is over, it's really over!
えーい！
Yay!
あしたは学校だね！会社だね！
Tomorrow is school, work...
ええ...
Yay...
見てくれてありがとう…
Thank you for watching...
やっと形にできて、夢が叶いました！
I finally brought it to life, and my dream came true!
私はもっともっと輝いて
I will shine brighter and brighter,
そんな姿を全部魅せたい！！
and show you all of my sides!!
もっと素敵な私を見せられるように
So I can show you an even more wonderful me,
がんばります！何卒！
I'll do my best! Please support me!